Next part of our seated asanas, or postures, is navasana, or a boat pose.
And you may have seen this in other exercise programs, Pilates and things like that.
So what you'll do is come to a seated position and then you'll slightly rock back on to your sacrum.
As you come back on to your sacrum, you can use your hands at first, if you want if you're just starting out, or use your hands behind your legs.
So what you'll do is you'll bring your legs up.
For beginners, you want to go to about a ninety degree angle and let your arms reach out towards the wall in front of you.
For a more advanced student, you can slowly straighten one leg and then the other.
So you bring yourself out, engage the core and reach energy out from your fingers, and if you're shaking like I just was then you want to come to a more bent position.
And then you can try again, challenge yourself.
If you have tight hip flexors, tight hamstrings, or any tightness in your lower back, it will be hard to straighten your legs.
So find the fullest expression for you, and go only to that point and then that will go into engaging the core rather than pulling into your back or any other part of your body.
And that is navasana or boat pose.